Colm, Gerhard; Records ger029
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under his supervision) for the National Planning Association, 1952-1968; 5; 47 file folders
  - "Statement of Gerhard Colm before the Subcommittee on Fiscal Policy of the Joint Economic Committee", 1957 April 24; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 16)
  - "Statement of Gerhard Colm, Chief Economist, National Planning Association before the House Ways and Means Committee", 1959 June 11; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 17)
  - Long-Range Projections for Economic Growth: the American Economy in 1970. A Staff Report. Planning Pamphlet No. 107, 1959 October (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 18)
  - "The Economic Outlook for 1960", 1959 December (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 19)
  - "The Economic Outlook for 1961", 1960 December (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 20)
  - "Economic Prognosis as Basis of Economic Policy", 1961 January (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 21)
  - "Targets for U.S. Economic Growth in the Early 60s", 1961 January 6; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 22)
  - "Targets for U.S. Economic Growth. A Statement by the NPA Steering Committee and A Staff Report by Gerhard Colm", 1961 January 6; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 23)
  - "A Joint Statement on The Rise of Chronic Unemployment", 1961 April 3; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 24)
  - "Budgetary Projections in the Framework of Economic Projections and their Adaptations", 1961 July; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 25)
  - "Budgetary Projections in the Framework of Economic Projections and Planning. Concluding Comments", 1961 September; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 26)
  - "Statement by Gerhard Colm before The Ways and Means Committee of the United States House of Representatives", 1962 July 26; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 27)
  - "Economic Potentials and Prospects: A New Look", 1963 June 1; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 28)
  - "World Economic Research in an Age of Competitive Coexistence", 1964 March (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 29)
  - "The Use and Misuse of Statistics", 1964 April (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 30)
  - "The Economic Outlook for 1965", 1964 December (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 31)
  - Modernizing the American Economy. A Joint Statement by the NPA Joint Subcommittee on Improving America's International Competitive Position and the NPA Steering Committee. National Planning Association, Special Report No. 61, 1964 December (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 32)
  - "Two Economic Reports: Canada and the United States", 1965 February (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 33)
  - "Economic Aspects of Technological Development", 1966 May 17; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 34)
  - "Comments on Price-Wage Guideposts", 1966 November (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 35)
  - "The Economic Outlook for 1967", 1966 December (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 36)
  - "Response by Gerhard Colm to Inquiry on Federally-Sponsored Social Research from the House Government Operations Committee, Research and Technical Programs Subcommittee", 1966 December 23; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 37)
  - "Statement of Gerhard Colm on The Economic Report of the President of January 1967, prepared for the hearing of the Joint Economic Committee", 1967 February 21; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 38)
  - "Short and Long-term Outlooks", 1967 April; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 39)
  - "Re: Comments on SDC's View of 1988", 1967 July 24; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 40)
  - "The Economic Outlook for 1967", 1967 December (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 41)
  - "'Questions' related to the Report of the Economic Advisors, to W. Heller's writings, and to the 1968 Forecast by Gerhard Colm (National Planning Assoc.)", Undated (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 42)
  - Integration of National Planning and Budgeting. Planning Methods Series No. 5, 1968 March (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 43)
  - "Hearings before the Joint Economic Committee on Implications of the Kerner Report: Employment and Manpower Problems in the Cities", 1968 June 4; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 44)
  - "The Next Step: Concerted Planning". Mimeographed address, 1968 October 24 (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 45)
  - Program Planning for national goals. Planning Pamphlet No. 125, 1968 November (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 46)
  - "The Economic Outlook for 1969", 1968 December (Box 2 (5-Publications and papers prepared by Colm (or under), Folder 47)
- Manuscripts by others, Undated; 6; 14 file folders
  - "Experiences in the Use of Social Accounting in Public Policy in the United States", Undated; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (6-Manuscripts by others), Folder 48)
  - "The National Peril. An International Committee Statement", Undated; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (6-Manuscripts by others), Folder 49)
  - Bloch, Ernest. "The Effect of Foreign Investment on the Balance of Payments: Comment", 1951; reprint (Box 2 (6-Manuscripts by others), Folder 50)
  - Denison, Edward F. "National Goals for Americans", Undated; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (6-Manuscripts by others), Folder 51)
  - Diwan, Romesh K. "Identification of the Elasticity of Factor Substitution when Factor Markets are Imperfect", 1967 December 8; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (6-Manuscripts by others), Folder 52)
  - Eynern, Gert von, Undated; reprint (Box 2 (6-Manuscripts by others), Folder 53)
  - Mann, Fritz Karl, Undated; reprint (Box 2 (6-Manuscripts by others), Folder 54)
  - Nelson, Benjamin, Undated; reprint (Box 2 (6-Manuscripts by others), Folder 55)
  - Pantuliano, C. B. "The Cyclical Performance of Federal Cash Receipts and Expenditures, 1953-1961", 1963 March 28; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (6-Manuscripts by others), Folder 56)
  - Rechtenwald, Horst Claus, Undated; reprint (Box 2 (6-Manuscripts by others), Folder 57)
  - Schiller, Karl, Undated; reprint (Box 2 (6-Manuscripts by others), Folder 58)
  - Schmidt, Kurt, Undated; reprint (Box 2 (6-Manuscripts by others), Folder 59)
  - von der Gablentz, Otto Heinrich, Undated; reprint (Box 2 (6-Manuscripts by others), Folder 60)
  - Wallich, Henry C. and William J. Dodson. "Economic Models and Black Economic Development", Undated; mimeographed typescript (Box 2 (6-Manuscripts by others), Folder 61)
- Miscellaneous materials, 1955-1967; 7; 6 file folders
  This series consists of additional publications of the National Planning Association as well as miscellaneous materials in German and in English.
  - National Planning Association. Individual issues of Looking Ahead, 1955-1967 (Box 2 (7-Miscellaneous materials), Folder 62)
  - National Planning Association. Press releases, 1960-1961 (Box 2 (7-Miscellaneous materials), Folder 63)
  - National Planning Association. Miscellaneous publications, Undated (Box 2 (7-Miscellaneous materials), Folder 64)
  - Miscellaneous materials, English, Undated (Box 2 (7-Miscellaneous materials), Folder 65)
  - Miscellaneous materials, German, Undated (Box 2 (7-Miscellaneous materials), Folder 66-67)